Hi my name is Penghui and today I'll talk about Market Failure.
So let's start with the definition of Market Failure.
It is the situation that happens when
the allocation of goods and services by the free market is inefficient.
This means that benefits are not maximized
based on the combination of goods and services that are currently in place.
So this implies that there can be
a better combination of goods and services such that
the benefits are actually maximized for the market.
So there are a couple of different types of market failure.
Basically imperfect competition which are your monopolies, oligopolies and so on.
Externalities which are your positive and negative externalities.
and lastly public goods.
So there are actually two more kinds of market failure
but I won't go into it because they're not in the H2 syllabus.
That is information asymmetry and the bounded rationality theorem.